Do not trust anyone. Do not show emotion. Do not fall asleep.
The Invasion is a horror, mystery, science fiction
film directed by Oliver Hirschbiegel.
Washington, D.C.
psychologist Carol Bennell and her colleague Dr.
Ben Driscoll are the only two people on Earth who are aware of
an epidemic running rampant through the city.
They discover an alien virus aboard a crashed space shuttle that transforms anyone
who comes into contact with it into unfeeling drones while they sleep.
Carol realizes her son holds the key to stopping the spread of the
plague and she races to find him before it is too late.
Carol Bennell, played by Nicole Kidman.
Ben Driscoll, played by Daniel Craig.
Oliver, played by Jackson Bond.
Tucker Kaufman, played by Jeremy Northam.
Dr. Stephen Galeano, played by Jeffrey Wright.
Wendy Lenk, played by Veronica Cartwright.
The Invasion is a 2007 American science fiction horror film directed by Oliver
Hirschbiegel, written by David Kajganich, and starring Nicole Kidman and Daniel Craig.
Unhappy with the original cut of the film, the studio hired The Wachowskis for
additional writing and James McTeigue to re-shoot some scenes.
The plot follows a psychiatrist (Kidman) in Washington, D.C.
who finds those around her turning into emotionless beings shortly after a Space
Shuttle crashes to Earth, bringing with it mysterious alien spores.
Development of the film began in 2004.
Warner Bros.
hired David Kajganich to write what was intended to be a relatively straightforward remake of the 1956 film
Invasion of the Body Snatchers, but Kajganich amended the story to reflect contemporary times.
Principal photography began in September 2005.
Released on August 17, 2007, the film was a commercial failure and
received primarily negative reviews from critics.
The Invasion is the fourth film adaptation of the 1955 novel The Body Snatchers by Jack Finney following Don Siegel's 1956 film
Invasion of the Body Snatchers, Philip Kaufman's 1978 remake of the same name, and Abel Ferrara's 1993 film Body Snatchers.
The film explores themes of escape, sleep, flu, alien, remake.
The tone is intense and dark and thought_provoking.